B1.
Simon is learning about the weather in different places around the world.
Here is a recording about the weather in December in four different cities – Moscow, Shanghai, Cairo and Sydney.
Listen with Simon and complete the table below.
In December, the average temperature in Moscow, Russia, is usually below zero degrees.
There is a lot of snow and the weather is cold, wet and windy.
The city is quite dark at the start of winter, with only about six or seven hours of daylight every day.
In Shanghai, China, the average temperature in December is a few degrees above zero.
Because it is next to the sea, Shanghai does not get very cold.
Winter in Shanghai can be quite wet.
It often rains, but seldom snows.
In Cairo, Egypt, December is a winter month, but it is not cold, with an average temperature above ten degrees Celsius.
The weather is often nice, but is usually cloudy.
December is a summer month in Sydney, Australia.
It usually has an average temperature above twenty degrees Celsius, but it is sometimes much hotter.
The weather is great.
On average, there are about nine hours of sunshine every day, and not much rain.